jacquesmattheij.com 2014-11-08

# Key terms – Privacy & Terms – Google

  * Affiliates
  * Anonymous identifier
  * Application data cache
  * Browser web storage
  * Cookie
  * Device
  * Google Account
  * HTTP Referrer
  * IP address
  * Non-personally identifiable information
  * Personal information
  * Pixel tag
  * Sensitive Categories
  * Sensitive personal information
  * Server logs
  * Unique device identifier

## Affiliates

An affiliate is an entity that belongs to the Google group of companies. 

## Anonymous identifier

An anonymous identifier is a random string of characters that is used for the same purposes as a cookie on platforms, including certain mobile devices, where cookie technology is not available. 

## Application data cache

An application data cache is a data repository on a device. It can, for example, enable a web application to run without an internet connection and improve the performance of the application by enabling faster loading of content. 

## Browser web storage

Browser web storage enables websites to store data in a browser on a device. When used in "local storage" mode, it enables data to be stored across sessions (for example, so that the data are retrievable even after the browser has been closed and reopened). One technology that facilitates web storage is HTML 5. 

## Cookie

A cookie is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the website again, the cookie allows that site to recognize your browser. Cookies may store user preferences and other information. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some website features or services may not function properly without cookies. 

## Device

A device is a computer that can be used to access Google services. For example, a device could be a desktop, tablet or smartphone. 

## Google Account

You may access some of our services by signing up for a Google Account and providing us with some personal information (typically your name, email address and a password). This account information will be used to authenticate you when you access Google services and protect your account from unauthorized access by others. You can edit or terminate your account at any time through your Google Account settings. 

## HTTP Referrer

An HTTP Referrer is information transmitted to a destination webpage by a web browser, typically when you click a link to that webpage. The HTTP Referrer contains the URL of the last webpage the browser visited. 

## IP address

Every computer connected to the Internet is assigned a unique number known as an Internet protocol (IP) address. Since these numbers are usually assigned in country-based blocks, an IP address can often be used to identify the country from which a computer is connecting to the Internet. 

## Non-personally identifiable information

This is information that is recorded about users so that it no longer reflects or references an individually identifiable user. 

## Personal information

This is information which you provide to us which personally identifies you, such as your name, email address or billing information, or other data which can be reasonably linked to such information by Google. 

## Pixel tag

A pixel tag is a type of technology placed on a website or within the body of an email for the purpose of tracking activity on websites, or when emails are opened or accessed, and is often used in combination with cookies. 

## Sensitive Categories

An advertising category may be sensitive if it relates to topics such as race, religion, sexual orientation or health. When showing you tailored ads, we may associate a cookie or anonymous identifier with interests such as "Cooking and Recipes" or "Air Travel," but not with sensitive categories. We impose a similar policy on our advertisers. 

## Sensitive personal information

This is a particular category of personal information relating to confidential medical facts, racial or ethnic origins, political or religious beliefs or sexuality. 

## Server logs

Like most websites, our servers automatically record the page requests made when you visit our sites. These “server logs” typically include your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. 

Here is an example of a typical log entry where the search is for “cars”, followed by a breakdown of its parts: 

    123.45.67.89 - 25/Mar/2003 10:15:32 -  
    http://www.google.com/search?q=cars -  
    Firefox 1.0.7; Windows NT 5.1 - 740674ce2123e969

  * `123.45.67.89` is the Internet Protocol address assigned to the user by the user’s ISP; depending on the user’s service, a different address may be assigned to the user by their service provider each time they connect to the Internet; 
  * `25/Mar/2003 10:15:32` is the date and time of the query; 
  * [`http://www.google.com/search?q=cars`](http://www.google.com/search?q=cars) is the requested URL, including the search query; 
  * `Firefox 1.0.7; Windows NT 5.1` is the browser and operating system being used; and 
  * `740674ce2123a969` is the unique cookie ID assigned to this particular computer the first time it visited Google. (Cookies can be deleted by users. If the user has deleted the cookie from the computer since the last time s/he visited Google, then it will be the unique cookie ID assigned to the user the next time s/he visits Google from that particular computer).

## Unique device identifier

A unique device identifier is a string of characters that is incorporated into a device by its manufacturer and can be used to uniquely identify that device (for example an IMEI-number of a mobile phone). Different device identifiers vary in how permanent they are, whether they can be reset by users, and how they can be accessed. A given device may have several different unique device identifiers. Unique device identifiers can be used for various purposes, including security and fraud detection, syncing services such as a user’s email inbox, remembering the user’s preferences and providing relevant advertising.
